Up to this point a finite automaton consumes a character of input
至此，有限自动机消耗输入的一个字符
every time it makes a move. So if you can't make any move at all, the input
每次它有动作的时候。所以如果你根本不能动，输入的
pointer advances. Now we're talking about a new kind of move, the epsilon move and
指针前进。现在我们在讨论一种新的动作，ε动作，
the idea behind the epsilon move is that the machine can make a state transition
epsilon移动背后的想法是机器可以进行状态转换
without consuming input, So for example if I have my states and I'm in state A and my
而不消耗输入，例如，如果我有我的州，并且我处于状态A和我的
input. And let's just say that we have x1, x2, x3 and for some reason we're about to
输入。假设我们有x1，x2，x3，出于某种原因，我们将要
read x2. When we make an Epsilon move the machine changes state but the input
阅读x2。当我们移动Epsilon时，机器会改变状态，但输入
pointer stays in exactly the same place. So the new configuration of the machine
指针保持在完全相同的位置。所以这台机器的新配置
that reinstate b, but our input pointer is still waiting to meet x2. So, you can
这恢复了b，但我们的输入指针仍在等待与x2相遇。所以，你可以
think of an epsilon move is a kind of free move from the machine it can, it can move
想想看，ε移动是一种自由移动，它可以从机器上自由移动，它可以移动
to a different state without consuming any input. And just to be clear here the
转换到不同的状态，而不消耗任何输入。在这里我只想说清楚
machine does not have to make the epsilon move. It's a choice so they can decide
机器不必使ε移动。这是一个选择，这样他们就可以决定
whether to make the epsilon move or not. Now epsilon move, the first time we have
是否使ε移动。现在埃西隆开始行动，这是我们第一次
mentioned the possibility that a finite automata might have a choice and what
提到了有限自动机可能有选择的可能性
moves it makes. There's actually an important distinction between automata
它做出的动作。实际上自动机和自动机之间有一个重要的区别
that have choices and those have don't. So deterministic finite automata have two
有选择的和没有选择的。所以确定性有限自动机有两个
properties, first of all, they have no epsilon moves so they must always consumed
属性，首先，它们没有epsilon移动，因此必须始终使用
input. And second, they only have one transition per input per state. What do I
输入。其次，每个状态的每个输入只有一个转换。我该怎么做
mean by that? That means that if I look at any state in the deterministic automaton,
你的意思是？这意味着如果我观察确定性自动机中的任何状态，
they can never have something like this where they have two possible moves for the
他们永远不会有这样的事情，因为他们有两个可能的动作
same input. All the outgoing edges in the deterministic automaton must have
同样的输入。确定性自动机中的所有传出边必须具有
different input labels. And then Nondeterministic Finite Automata are just
不同的输入标签。那么非确定性有限自动机就是
those not deterministic. So in particular a Nondeterministic Automata can have
那些不是确定性的。因此，特别是非确定性自动机可以具有
epsilon moves so it can choose to move to another state without consuming input and
Epsilon会移动，因此它可以选择移动到另一个状态，而无需消耗输入和
it could also have multiple transitions for one input in a given state so
对于处于给定状态的一个输入，它还可以有多个转换，因此
something like this, is okay for a Nondeterministic Automata. Yeah. Let me
像这样的东西，对于非确定性自动机来说是可以的。嗯。让我
just point out really epsilon moves are enough to create a non-deterministic
只需指出，ε的移动就足以创建一个不确定的
automata and then at the second case where you have multiple transitions on the same
自动机，然后在第二种情况下，在同一自动机上有多个转换
input can be simulated just by a slightly more complicated machine with epsilon move
输入可以通过带有epsilon移动稍微复杂的机器来模拟
so for example I can draw this machine in the following way. I can have or I can
举个例子，我可以用下面的方法画这台机器。我可以拥有或者我可以
simulate the machine that circled there in the following way. I can have a state with
按照以下方式模拟在那里转圈的机器。我可以和一个州
two epsilon moves and then. Each of those states has a move on A so I were to label
两个ε动作，然后。这些州中的每一个都有A上的移动，所以我给A贴上标签
the states one, two, and three. Then this would be the state that corresponds to
州一，州二，州三。则这将是对应于
one. And this would be the state that corresponds to two and this state be, be
一。这就是对应于2的状态，这个状态是，是
the state that corresponds to three. So anytime that we have multiple moves out of
与三相对应的状态。所以每当我们有多个动作离开的时候
the state on a single input we could always replace that by a few more states
一个输入上的状态，我们总是可以用更多的几个状态来替换它
with epsilon moves and have every state in the machine only have a single transition
使用epsilon移动，并使机器中的每个状态只有一个转换
for every possible input. So really the only fundamental difference between the
所有可能的输入。所以真正的根本区别在于
deterministic automata and non-deterministic automata is w hether
确定性自动机和非确定性自动机是两种不同的自动机
they have epsilon moves or not. A key property of a Deterministic Automata is
他们有没有埃西隆动作。确定性自动机的一个关键性质是
that it can only take one path through the state graph per input. So this is per
它在每个输入中只能采用一条通过状态图的路径。所以这是PER
input. What do I mean by that? Well, the automaton always begins at the start state
输入。我这么说是什么意思？嗯，自动机总是从开始状态开始
and let's take a very simple input string like ABC and if we can look at the
让我们来看一个非常简单的输入字符串，比如abc，如果我们可以看一下
sequence of states that the Deterministic Automaton will take, For that input, this
确定性自动机对于该输入将采用的状态序列，这
path through the state graph is completely determined by the input because again it
通过状态图的路径完全由输入确定，因为它
has no choice. In a given state, this can be one transition label day and this
别无选择。在给定状态下，这可以是一个转换标签日，并且此
continue to a state that it only has one transition labeled b and that goes to
继续到这样一种状态，即它只有一个标记为b的转换，该状态将转到
another state that only has one transition labeled c. And so, every input determines
另一种状态，它只有一个标记为c的转换。因此，每个输入都确定
the path through the state graph of the automata will take. And, this is not true
通过自动机的状态图的路径将采用。而且，这不是真的
for Nondeterministic Automata. So, it might be for example. That beginning in
用于非确定自动机。所以，它可能是一个例子。开始于
the start state and on input a that there is some state I can go to on that input a
开始状态，且在输入A上存在我可以在输入A上转到某个状态
but there maybe another transition labeled a that would take me to a different state
但也许还有另一个标记为a的过渡会把我带到一个不同的状态
so the automaton might be able to go to one of two different states and again
所以自动机可能会进入两种不同的状态中的一种，然后再一次
there might be also epsilon transitions. And so what happens with Nondeterministic
也可能存在ε跃迁。那么，非确定性会发生什么呢？
Automata is that in general as they proceed to the state graph is they execute
自动机通常是指，当它们前进到状态图时，它们会执行
on the input, they could wind up in any number of different states. Okay. And the
在输入时，它们可能会进入任意数量的不同状态。好吧。以及
rule with the non-deterministic automaton about when it accepts is that it accepts
非确定性自动机关于它何时接受的规则是它接受
if any path accepts. So if NFA Accepts, If some Choices Lead to an accepting state at
如果有任何路径接受的话。因此，如果NFA接受，如果某些选择导致接受状态为
the end of the input. Now there's a [inaudible] automaton, I can choose what
输入的末尾。现在有个[听不见的]自动机，我可以选择
move to make and as long as there are some choice it can make, then we'll get it to
移动到作出，只要有一些选择它可以做，然后我们会得到它
an accepting state. So let's say switching colors here that you know this was an
一种接受的状态。所以让我们假设在这里切换颜色，你知道这是一个
accepting state down here and they took this path. Then it would accept and maybe
在这里接受州政府，他们走了这条路。然后它就会接受，也许
all of these other pass are rejecting pass, that doesn't matter. As long as
所有这些其他的传球都是拒绝传球的，这都无关紧要。只要
there is one path, a one set of choices the NFA could make to get it to an
有一条途径，NFA可以做出一套选择来将它带到
accepting state at the end of the input, then we say that, that string is in the
在输入的末尾接受状态，那么我们就说，该字符串在
language of the NFA. The fact that NFAs could get into multiple different states
NFA的语言。事实上，NFA可能会进入多个不同的状态
depending on the choices they make during a run is important and will actually play
取决于他们在跑步过程中做出的选择是很重要的，而且实际上会起作用
central role in the future video, so we're gonna do a quick example here to just make
在未来的视频中扮演核心角色，所以我们将在这里做一个简单的示例
sure that this is clear. So here's a little automaton and note that it is
当然，这一点很清楚。这里有一个小机器人，请注意，它是
Nondeterministic Automata from the start state there are two possible moves input
非确定性自动机从开始状态有两种可能的移动输入
zero. And what we're going to do is just walk through in execution of this machine
零。我们要做的就是在这台机器的执行过程中
on a sample input and see what different states it can get into. So we begin at the
在一个示例输入上，看看它可以进入哪些不同的状态。所以我们从
start state and we should probably label our states actually so that we can refer
开始状态，我们可能应该标记我们的状态，这样我们就可以引用
to them. Let's call them A, B, and C. And let's say at the first input is one and so
对他们来说。我们称它们为A、B和C。假设第一个输入是1，所以
what does that mean? That means we'll take this transition. We'll just go from the
那是什么意思？这意味着我们将接受这个过渡。我们就从
start state and come back to the start state and so the set of states that the
开始状态并返回到开始状态，因此
machine could be in after the first transition is just the set A. So it's
机器可能在第一次转换后就是集合A，所以它是
guaranteed to still be in the start state. So there's no, no choices with the first
保证仍然处于启动状态。所以第一个没有，没有选择
move. Now let's say at the second input character is a zero and now we do have a
移动。现在让我们假设第二个输入字符是零，现在我们确实有一个
choice. We could either go to state B or we could go to state A. And, we could
选择。我们可以去B州，也可以去A州。
think of this then as a set of possibilities that after we execute this
那么可以把这看作是一系列的可能性，在我们执行完这项任务之后
move, this transition, the machine could be in anyone of the set of states and
移动，这个转换，机器可以处于这组状态中的任何一个，并且
actually this completely characterizes the possibilities for the machine. We've only
实际上，这完全体现了这台机器的可能性。我们只有
read the second input character and now we could be in a set of states, okay? And we
读取第二个输入字符，现在我们可能处于一组状态，好吗？而我们
could be either in state a or in state b. And so now let's say we read another zero.
可能是在状态a，也可能是在状态b，那么现在假设我们读取的是另一个0。
And where could we go then, well if we're in state B we could make the transition to
那么我们可以去哪里呢，如果我们在B州，我们可以过渡到
state C but if we're in state A then we'll make the transition either to state B or
状态C，但如果我们在状态A，那么我们将转换到状态B或
again to state A. So in fact we could be in anyone of the three states if we read
再回到A州，事实上，如果我们读到这三个州中的任何一个，我们都有可能处于这三个州中的任何一个州
another zero. Okay? And now you, I think you can see w hat the rule is. So in every
又是一个零。好吧?现在你，我想你可以看到规则是什么了。所以在每一个
step a Nondeterministic Automata is in a set of states of the machine and when it
步骤非确定自动机处于机器的一组状态，并且当它
reason, the input we consider all the possible moves it can make to compute the
原因是，我们考虑它可以进行的所有可能的移动来计算
complete set of states that could be in at the next step of the machine. Okay? And
机器下一步可能处于的完整状态集。好吧?和
then the, the, finally has to decide whether the machine accepts while we look
然后，最后要决定我们看的时候机器是不是接受
at the final state after the last bid of input is red and if there's any I'm sorry,
在最后一次出价输入后的最终状态是红色的，如果有的话，我很抱歉，
we look at the last set of states after the last input character is red and if
我们查看最后一个输入字符为红色之后的最后一组状态，如果
there's any final state in that set, then the machine accepts and in this case,
在该集合中有任何最终状态，然后机器接受，在这种情况下，
after we read zero, we see that in accepting state c is in the set of
在我们读取零之后，我们看到在接受中，状态c在
possible states. So what that means is, if there was some sort of choices that the
可能的状态。所以这意味着，如果有某种选择，
machine could make, that we'll get it into the final state at the end of the input
我们将在输入结束时使其进入最终状态
and so with the machine. Accepts this input, okay? So if there's a final state
机器也是如此。接受这个输入，好吗？所以如果有一个最终状态
in the final set of possible states, then the Nondeterministic machine accepts. It
在最后一组可能的状态中，非确定性机器接受。它
turns out that NFA's and DFA's are recognized exactly the same languages and
事实证明，NFA和DFA被识别为完全相同的语言，并且
particularly the regular languages. So NFA's, DFA's and regular expressions all
尤其是常规语言。所以NFA、DFA和正则表达式
have equivalent power. They can only specify regular languages. Dfa's are
拥有同等的能量。它们只能指定常规语言。DFA是
definitely faster to execute primarily or entirely because there are no choices to
主要或全部执行的速度肯定更快，因为没有选择
consider so a DFA and just follow a single path through the state graph where with
将其视为DFA，在状态图中只遵循一条路径，其中
NFA we have to keep track potentially of the set of choices in the NFA and we might
我们必须潜在地跟踪NFA中的选择集，并且我们可能
be in set of states. However there are some advantages to NFA so they are in
处于一组状态。然而，NFA也有一些优势，所以他们在
general much smaller. And DFA's, In fact, they can be exponentially smaller so the
一般要小得多。而DFA的，事实上，它们可以指数级地更小，所以
smallest. Nfa, Maybe much, much smaller than the smallest equivalent DFA for the
最小的。NFA，可能比最小的等效DFA要小得多
same language, And, there's, so essentially there's a space time tradeoff
同样的语言，而且，本质上说，这是一个时空的权衡
between NFAs and DFAs. Nfas might be more compact but DFAs will be faster to
在NFA和DFAS之间。NFA可能更紧凑，但DFA将更快地
execute.
执行。